MUHAMMAD TAHA MUKHTAR

tahamukhtar20@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/tahamukhtar20 | github.com/tahamukhtar20 | +923310148548

INTRODUCTION

Highly skilled and motivated programmer with an impressive track record of delivering exceptional results. With a diverse range of projects under my belt, I am well-versed in various programming languages and possess a deep understanding of software development methodologies. I have a lot of experience developing software, have been doing it for about 2 years now and have many different projects related to it, some of those are listed below. Also check out my portfolio website <u>tahamukhtar20.vercel.app</u>.

EXPERIENCE

AUF 2023 - PRESENT

OneScreen Solutions (Junior Software Developer)

MAY 2023 - AUG 2023

OneScreen Solutions (Research & Development intern)

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

FIVERR, (Freelance, Level 1 Seller)

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCES, (National University of Sciences and Technology, Islamabad)

NOTABLE PROJECTS

DILJO (Fundraising Web Application)

A Web application made with NEXT.js, Tailwind CSS, Stripe Payment Gateway, Google Maps API, and Pocketbase. Automated the donation system at NUST and designed it as a flexible fundraising platform similar to GoFundMe with an added element of gamification, i.e Achievement System. Backend was made with pocketbase which is implemented in Golang with SQLite.

JACOKIN AUTO

A Web application made with NEXT.js, NEST.js Backend, Mongo DB, Typescript, SCSS, Redux, JWT etc, this was a freelance project, which I made with a team of developers.

NUST Student Support Web Application

Built a web application using FAST API with SQLite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap. Implemented deep learning models for grade prediction through peer comparison. Uses web scraping by the requests module and beautiful soup. This Project was made by me and another pair developer in the beginning of my web development journey and I'm still proud of this project to this day.

MAQUETTE

A web application made using NEXT.js with typescript, and Firebase. Made for a french iron curtain store, with custom features asked by the client, this was a freelance project on fiverr.

For a comprehensive overview of my projects, please visit my GitHub.

SKILLS

- Frontend Web Development: HTML, CSS, JS, React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, React Query, Redux, Redux Thunk etc.
- Mobile App Development: React Native, Kotlin, Java
- Backend Development & DB: Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, Sessions, JWT, MVC architecture, Prisma, Mongoose, Mongo
 DB, SQL etc
- Data Analytics & Web Scraping: Pandas, Seaborn, Matpltlib, Scikit Learn, Numpy, NLTK, Requests, Beautiful Soup, Selenium.
- Programming Languages: Typescript, Javascript, Java, Python
- Miscellaneous: Git/Version Control, CI/CD, Github Actions, Regex, Docker etc.

NOTABLE CERTIFICATIONS/COURSES

- **Coursera:** Advanced React, React Basics, Higher Order Components in React Typescript.
- **Hackerrank:** Problem Solving (Intermediate), JavaScript (Intermediate), Python, CSS, SQL.
- DataCamp: Data Analytics using Pandas, DataViz using Seaborn, Python Fundamentals.
- Sololearn: C++ complete course